Guide to the Léonie Adams and William Troy Papers
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
- Correspondence, 1920-1980, undated; Series I; 4.0 linear feet (4 boxes)
  - Léonie Adams Correspondence
    - Correspondence filed by subject
      - Bollingen Prize, 1955 (Box 4, Folder 302)
      - Troy's writings, 1961-1968 (Box 4, Folder 303)
      - Conversion to Christianity, 1951-1952 (Box 4, Folder 304)
  - William Troy Correspondence
    This subseries is arranged alphabetically by correspondent. A small amount of unidentified correspondence is filed at the end of the subseries.
    - "A" general, 1925-1960 (Box 4, Folder 305)
    - Adams, Henrietta R., 1933 February 16 (Box 4, Folder 306)
    - Adams, Léonie, 1932-1956,undated (Box 4, Folder 307-310)
    - "B" general, 1922-1960 (Box 4, Folder 311)
    - Barnes, Anna K., 1925-1929 (Box 4, Folder 312)
    - Belitt, Ben, 1936-1967 (Box 4, Folder 313-314)
    - Berdan, John M., 1933, undated (Box 4, Folder 315)
    - Bollingen Foundation, 1956 (Box 4, Folder 316)
    - The Bookman, 1929-1931 (Box 4, Folder 317)
    - Brandeis, Irma, undated (Box 4, Folder 318)
    - Burke, Kenneth, 1957, 1962 (Box 4, Folder 319)
    - "C" general, 1933-1961 (Box 4, Folder 320)
    - Cazamian, L., 1929 December 14 (Box 4, Folder 321)
    - Chamberlain, John, 1929-1930, undated (Box 4, Folder 322)
    - Cohen, Gustave, 1943 (Box 4, Folder 323)
    - Colum, Padraic, undated (Box 4, Folder 324)
    - Cross, Wilbur L., 1937 April 3 (Box 4, Folder 325)
    - Cummings, E. E., 1948 April 19 (Box 4, Folder 326)
    - Dell, Floyd, undated (Box 4, Folder 327)
    - Dennison, George, undated (Box 4, Folder 328)
    - The Dial, 1921-1925 (Box 4, Folder 329)
    - Dollard, W. A. S., 1931-1933 (Box 4, Folder 330)
    - Dupee, Fred, 1937-1967, undated (Box 4, Folder 331)
    - "E" general, 1952, undated (Box 4, Folder 332)
    - Eberhart, Richard, 1942 April 4 (Box 4, Folder 333)
    - Eisendrath, William N. Jr., 1928-1930, undated (Box 4, Folder 334)
    - "F" general, 1936-1968 (Box 4, Folder 335)
    - Farrell, James T., 1933-1954 (Box 4, Folder 336)
    - Fernandez, Ramon, 1930 May 13 (Box 4, Folder 337)
    - Fitts, Norman, 1922, undated (Box 4, Folder 338)
    - Fitzgerald, F. Scott, undated (Box 4, Folder 339)
    - Ford, Ford Madox, 1938 November 17 (Box 4, Folder 340)
    - Fowlie, Wallace, 1941, 1943 (Box 4, Folder 341)
    - Frank, Waldo, undated (Box 4, Folder 342)
    - "G" general, 1930-1961 (Box 4, Folder 343)
    - Goudiss, Alberta H., 1923-1924 (Box 4, Folder 344)
    - Gregory, Horace; Gregory, Marya, 1936, undated (Box 4, Folder 345)
    - "H" general, 1935, 1966, undated (Box 4, Folder 346)
    - Hazlitt, Henry, 1936 November 19 (Box 4, Folder 347)
    - Empty folder (Box 4, Folder 348)
    - Humphries, Rolfe, 1955 March 15 (Box 4, Folder 349)
    - "I-J" general, 1935, 1948-1961, undated (Box 4, Folder 350)
    - Kirstein, Lincoln, 1932-1933 (Box 4, Folder 351)
    - Krutch, Joseph W., 1936, undated (Box 4, Folder 352)
    - "L" general, 1941, 1959 (Box 4, Folder 353)
    - Laughlin, James, 1940-1941, undated (Box 4, Folder 354)
    - Lewis, Sinclair, 1941 June 8 (Box 4, Folder 355)
    - "M" general, 1923-1967 (Box 4, Folder 356)
    - Macdonald, Dwight, undated (Box 4, Folder 357)
    - Maritain, Jacques, 1941 February 22 (Box 4, Folder 358)
    - Marshall, Margaret, 1931, 1937, undated (Box 4, Folder 359)
    - Matthews, Elva, 1936-1947, undated (Box 4, Folder 360)
    - Mayer, Clara W., 1960-1967 (Box 4, Folder 361)
    - Merle, Robert, 1944-1956 (Box 4, Folder 362)
    - Miller, Henry, undated (Box 4, Folder 363)
    - Moore, Marianne, 1948 (Box 4, Folder 364)
    - "N" general, 1935-1962 (Box 4, Folder 365)
    - New Masses, 1935 November 6 (Box 4, Folder 366)
    - O'Faolain, Sean, 1932 October 15 (Box 4, Folder 367)
    - Ochshorn, Myron, 1950-1952 (Box 4, Folder 368)
    - Ogden, C. K., 1933 January 30 (Box 4, Folder 369)
    - Oxford University Press, 1946-1961 (Box 4, Folder 370)
    - "P" general, 1961-1963 (Box 4, Folder 371)
    - Partisan Review, 1936 (Box 4, Folder 372)
    - Patmore, Brigit, undated (Box 4, Folder 373)
    - Peyre, Henri, 1940-1943 (Box 4, Folder 374)
    - Phelps, Lyon, 1924 (Box 4, Folder 375)
    - Poetry, 1920-1921, undated (Box 4, Folder 376)
    - Porter, Katherine Anne, 1939, undated (Box 4, Folder 377)
    - Quinn, Father, undated (Box 4, Folder 378)
    - Ransom, John Crowe, 1934-1935 (Box 4, Folder 379)
    - Rodman, Selden, 1936, undated (Box 4, Folder 380)
    - Rosenfeld, Paul, 1928 October 11 (Box 4, Folder 381)
    - Rourke, Constance, 1936, 1938 (Box 4, Folder 382)
    - "S" general, 1919, 1935-1960 (Box 4, Folder 383)
    - Savage, Walter, 1953 (Box 4, Folder 384)
    - Sedgwick, William Ellery, 1941 (Box 4, Folder 385)
    - Simonson, Lee, 1939-1940 (Box 4, Folder 386)
    - Smart Set Publishing Co., 1924 (Box 4, Folder 387)
    - Snell, Ada L., 1924, undated (Box 4, Folder 388)
    - Stapelfeldt, E. Pelham, 1960, undated (Box 4, Folder 389)
    - Stein, Leo, 1928 March 13 (Box 4, Folder 390)
    - "T" general, undated (Box 4, Folder 391)
    - Tate, Allen, 1938-1960 (Box 4, Folder 392)
    - Transition, 1927 (Box 4, Folder 393)
    - "U" general, 1955-1970 (Box 4, Folder 394)
    - Van Doren, Mark, 1935-1942 (Box 4, Folder 395)
    - Volkening, Henry, 1930 March 26 (Box 4, Folder 396)
    - "W" general, 1923-1960 (Box 4, Folder 397)
    - Wahl, Jean, 1959, undated (Box 4, Folder 398)
    - Warren, Austin, 1943 February 26 (Box 4, Folder 399)
    - West, Rebecca, 1930 January 20 (Box 4, Folder 400)
    - Winters, Yvor, 1937 February 24 (Box 4, Folder 401)
    - "Y" general, 1925, undated (Box 4, Folder 402)
    - Yourcenar, Marguerite, 1941 March 27 (Box 4, Folder 403)
    - Zabel, Morton D., 1936-1937 (Box 4, Folder 404)
    - Zimbalist, Alina, undated (Box 4, Folder 405)
    - ___, Harold, 1938-1939 (Box 4, Folder 406)
    - ___, Mary, 1960 (Box 4, Folder 407)
    - Unidentified, 1923-1961, undated (Box 4, Folder 408)
- Writings, 1915-1973, undated; Series II; 2.0 linear feet (2 boxes)
  Series II. Writings is organized into two subseries: Léonie Adams Writings and William Troy Writings.
  The Writing series is comprised of holograph, typescript, and composite drafts, galley proofs, and printed versions of writings.
  The Léonie Adams Writings subseries contains poems, prose, childhood writings, and notes by Adams. It also includes writings by others about Adams's work. Poems includes correspondence and reviews regarding Poems: A Selection.
  The William Troy Writings subseries contains essays, poems, drama, literary and drama reviews, and a translation by Troy. It includes writings by others about Troy's work.
  - Léonie Adams Writings
    This subseries is arranged under three headings: Poems; Other Writings; and Writings of Others.
    - Poems
      Titles include individual poems and books of poetry.
      Material under this heading is arranged alphabetically by title. Folders created by Adams of various poems, published and unpublished, are filed following the alphabetical sequence.
      - "Apple in its Season," draft, holograph, 1967 January (Box 5, Folder 409)
      - "Dirge at the Edge of the Woods," drafts, holograph and typescript, undated (Box 5, Folder 409a)
      - "The Font in the Forest," drafts, holograph and typescript, undated (Box 5, Folder 410)
      - "Fourth St.," drafts, holograph, undated (Box 5, Folder 411)
      - "Goodbye Those Children," drafts, holograph, undated (Box 5, Folder 412)
      - High Falcon and Other Poems
        - Drafts, holograph and typescript, circa 1928 (Box 5, Folder 413-415)
        - Dustjacket, 1928 (Box 5, Folder 416)
      - "Light at Equinox," drafts, holograph and typescript, undated (Box 5, Folder 417)
      - "November Eve," drafts, typescript, undated (Box 5, Folder 418)
      - "O Grave," drafts, holograph and typescript, undated (Box 5, Folder 419)
      - "The People in the Park," drafts, holograph and typescript, undated (Box 5, Folder 420)
      - Poems: A Selection
        - Drafts, typescript, corrected, circa 1930 (Box 5, Folder 421-422)
        - Setting typescript, undated (Box 5, Folder 423-424)
        - Galleys, corrected, 1953-1954 (Folder 594 (Broadside))
        - Proofs, 1953-1954 (Box 5, Folder 425)
        - Correspondence, 1954 (Box 5, Folder 426)
        - Reviews, clippings, 1954
      - "Radio and Katydid," drafts, holograph and typescript, undated (Box 5, Folder 427)
      - "The Reminder," draft, typescript, [1929?] (Box 5, Folder 428)
      - "The River in the Meadow," printed version, 1954
      - "Runner from the Lots," drafts, holograph and typescript, undated (Box 5, Folder 429)
      - "The Summer Image," drafts, holograph and typescript, undated (Box 5, Folder 430)
      - Those Not Elect
        - Dustjacket, 1935 (Box 5, Folder 431)
        - Reviews, clippings, 1925-1926
      - "Thoughts on a Violet," drafts, holograph and typescript, undated (Box 5, Folder 432)
      - "The Vision at Morning," drafts, typescript, 1927, 1930 (Box 5, Folder 433)
      - "Words for the Raker of Leaves," drafts, holograph and typescript, undated (Box 5, Folder 434)
      - Childhood poems, 1909-1912 (Box 5, Folder 435)
      - Poems sent to Eleanor Philips, drafts, holograph and typescript, undated (Box 5, Folder 436-438)
      - Various poems, drafts, holograph, typescript and printed version, undated (Box 5, Folder 439-440)
      - "Unpublished poems," drafts, typescript and holograph, circa 1920s - 1930s (Box 5, Folder 441)
      - Clippings of poems published in The New Republic, undated (Box 5, Folder 442)
        Includes list of published poems
      - First drafts and variations, drafts, holograph and typescript, undated (Box 5, Folder 443)
      - Notes, undated (Box 5, Folder 444)
      - Clippings of poems, undated (Box 5, Folder 445)
    - Other Writings
      - "Apostate," printed version from The Barnard Bear, 1921 (Box 5, Folder 446)
      - Jezebel, printed version, undated (Box 5, Folder 447)
      - "The Tale of Tenjin," printed version from The Metropolitan Museum of Art's The Children's Bulletin, 1928 (Box 5, Folder 448)
    - Writings of Others
      - Clippings about Adams, 1926-1962, undated (Box 5, Folder 449-453)
  - William Troy Writings
    This subseries is arranged under five headings: Essays; Poems; Drama; Reviews and Other Writings; and Writings of Others.
    - Essays
      - Plans for book of essays, holograph and typescript notes, prospectus, and foreword, undated (Box 5, Folder 454-455)
      - "The Altar of Henry James," printed version from The New Republic, 1943 February 15 (Box 5, Folder 456)
      - Selected Essays
        - Draft, typescript, corrected, undated (Box 5, Folder 457-459)
        - Introduction and memoir, typescript photocopy, undated (Box 5, Folder 460)
          Includes photograph of Troy
        - Setting typescript, undated (Box 5, Folder 461-462)
        - Typescript photocopy, corrected, undated (Box 5, Folder 463-464)
        - Index cards, undated (Box 6, Folder 465)
        - Galleys, corrected, 1966-1967 (Folder 595 (Broadside))
        - Correspondence with Adams about the National Book Award, 1968 (Box 6, Folder 466)
        - Reviews, clippings and printed material, 1967-1968
        - Reviews and press on National Book Award, clippings, 1967-1968
    - Poems
      Printed versions from Elihu
      - "The Aegean", 1923 April (Box 6, Folder 467)
      - "Ballet", 1923 March (Box 6, Folder 468)
      - "Valley Youth", 1923 March (Box 6, Folder 469)
    - Drama
      - Plays, typescript drafts, undated (Box 6, Folder 470-471)
      - "The Prodigal," printed version from Elihu, 1923 February (Box 6, Folder 472)
    - Reviews and Other Writings
      - Literary and film reviews, clippings and tear sheets, circa 1920s-1940s (Box 6, Folder 473-489)
      - "White Knickers," printed version in Elihu, 1923 March (Box 6, Folder 490)
      - "Random Foot Notes: Reflections, More or Less, from an Imaginary Note Book," printed version from Elihu, 1923 April (Box 6, Folder 491)
      - Scrapbook of Troy reviews and essays, clippings, 1927-1930 (Box 6, Folder 492)
      - Review of James Joyce's Ulysses: A Study by Stuart Gilbert (from New York Times Book Review ), 1931 January 18
      - Childhood writings, circa 1910 (Box 6, Folder 493)
      - "Writings to be published," clippings and tear sheets, typescripts and typescript photocopies, undated (Box 6, Folder 494-496)
      - Selections: Gaspard de la Nuit by Louis Bertrand, translation from French to English and with note by Troy, draft, typescript, undated (Box 6, Folder 497)
      - Unidentified notes, undated (Box 6, Folder 498-499)
    - Writings of Others
      - "Letters by Rodger Casement," typescript copies, 1915-1929 (Box 7, Folder 500)
      - Tate, Allen. "A Memoir," typescript draft, undated (Box 7, Folder 501)
      - Simon, Joan. "Homage to William Troy," printed in Commonwealth, 1968 (Box 7, Folder 502)
- Professional Papers, 1922-1964, undated; Series III; 1.0 linear foot (1 box)
  Series III. Professional Papers is organized into two subseries: Léonie Adams and William Troy.
  This series contains professional papers of both Adams and Troy. The papers reflect their teaching, poetry readings, grants and awards, and participation in professional organizations.
  - Léonie Adams
    - League of Professional Groups of Foster and Ford, letters, 1932, 1964 (Box 7, Folder 503)
    - Programs from readings, 1944-1967, undated (Box 7, Folder 504-505)
      Includes program of joint reading with Troy, airline ticket, and itinerary
    - Library of Congress Annual Report, 1949 (Box 7, Folder 506)
    - Notes and printed material on Ezra Pound receiving the Bollingen prize, 1949 (Box 7, Folder 507)
    - Disassembled binder of writings, notes, and printed material on the Bollingen Prize, the Saturday Review of Literature, and the Library of Congress Consultant in Poetry, 1949-1952, undated (Box 7, Folder 508-509)
    - Columbia University Student Council Conference, excerpts, 1955 (Box 7, Folder 510)
    - Teaching notes, undated (Box 7, Folder 511)
  - William Troy
    - Teaching Materials
      - Lecture notes, typescript and holograph, undated (Box 7, Folder 512-513)
      - Bennington College, 1942 (Box 7, Folder 514)
      - New School University, 1946-1959, undated (Box 7, Folder 515-517)
      - Adult School at Montclair, 1946 (Box 7, Folder 518)
      - Rand School of Social Science, 1948 (Box 7, Folder 519)
      - On tragedy, 1953, undated (Box 7, Folder 520-525)
      - On literature and myth, undated (Box 7, Folder 526)
    - Poems for poetry course work, drafts, typescript and holograph, undated (Box 7, Folder 527-528)
    - Yale prize certificates, 1922, 1924 (Box 7, Folder 529)
    - American Field Service Fellowship for French University certificate, report and correspondence, 1929 (Box 7, Folder 530)
    - Guggenheim Foundation application, 1937 (Box 7, Folder 531)
    - Olivet Writers' Conference brochures and itinerary, 1938 (Box 7, Folder 532)
    - Modern Language Association, 1941 (Box 7, Folder 533)
    - Columbia University Graduate English Society meeting notices, 1951 (Box 7, Folder 534)
    - Fulbright materials, 1956, undated (Box 7, Folder 535)
- Photographs, circa 1920-1960, undated; Series IV; 5 folders
  This series chiefly consists of an album of photographs of Léonie Adams and William Troy, their friends, literary events, and their travels. Most of the photographs are from the period of their marriage, though some provide images of their lives before they met each other.
  - Early photographs of Adams, Troy, and family members, circa 1880-1910 (Box 7, Folder 536)
  - Photograph album, 1955-1956 (Box 7, Folder 537)
  - Loose snapshots removed from album, circa 1920-1960 (Box 7, Folder 538-539)
  - Postcards removed from album, undated (Box 7, Folder 540)
- Personal Papers, 1902-1971, undated; Series V; 1.25 linear feet (3 boxes)
  The series is arranged chronologically with a group of miscellaneous clippings filed at the end.
  The series contains personal papers of both Adams and Troy, as well as material collected by Adams and Troy on various subjects of interest, including teaching, editing, poets and poetry, and cancer of the larynx.
  - Troy's birth certificate, 1903 (Box 8, Folder 541)
  - Troy's early school records, 1921, undated (Box 8, Folder 542)
  - Troy's journals, 1919-1931 (Box 8, Folder 543-548)
  - Troy's Yale degree and other materials, 1929 (Box 8, Folder 549)
  - Troy's business card and identification card for the University of Paris, 1929, undated (Box 9, Folder 550)
  - Marriage certificate, 1933 (Box 9, Folder 551)
  - Tax form regarding fellowship award tax status, 1952 (Box 9, Folder 552)
  - Troy's medical insurance cards, 1954 (Box 9, Folder 553)
  - Various travel documents of Troy's, 1955-1958 (Box 9, Folder 554)
    Includes immunization cards, passport, and visa.
  - Various clippings about Troy, 1933-1934, 1967-1968, undated (Box 9, Folder 555)
  - James Joyce Society meeting notices, 1952, undated (Box 9, Folder 556)
  - "Souvenirs" of Josephine Adams, photograph, eulogy, and correspondence, 1971, undated (Box 9, Folder 557)
  - Written account of Adams's ancestor's travels and family from 1872, undated (Box 9, Folder 558)
  - Address book, undated (Box 9, Folder 559)
    Mostly blank
  - Notes, 1960, undated (Box 9, Folder 560-563)
    Includes notes from and on being in the hospital for larynx surgery
  - Miscellaneous notes and literary programs, 1923-1954, undated (Box 9, Folder 564-565)
  - Printed material and clippings collected by Adams and Troy
    - "The Editor at Home," unidentified author, Sunday Tribune, 1902 October 5 (Box 9, Folder 566)
    - Deming, Barbara. "The Peacemakers," Bennington College Bulletin, 1961 February (Box 9, Folder 567)
    - Fergusson, Francis. "The Humanity of the Greeks," lecture at Bennington College, 1941 (Box 9, Folder 568)
    - On T.S. Eliot, 1948-1949
    - On Ezra Pound and Bollingen Prize, 1949
    - On Wallace Stevens, William Carlos Williams and various poetry, 1949, 1954, undated; Stored in: Oversize Box 11, Folder 584 and Box 12, Folder 589
    - On Edmund Wilson, undated (Box 9, Folder 569)
    - On cancer of the larynx, undated (Box 9, Folder 570)
    - Miscellaneous clippings, 1899-1964 undated (Box 9, Folder 571-572)
  - Empty folders with Adams's notes, undated (Box 9)
- Oversize, 0.5 linear feet (2 boxes and 2 broadside folders)
  - Poems: A Selection, galley proofs (in Series II), 1953-1954 (Folder 594 (Broadside))
  - Poems: A Selection, reviews and clippings(in Series II), 1954 (Box 11, Folder 573)
  - "The River in the Meadow"(in Series II), 1954 (Box 11, Folder 574)
  - "Those Not Elect," reviews and clippings (in Series II), 1925-1926 (Box 11, Folder 575)
  - Clippings about Adams (in Series II), 1949-1962 (Box 11, Folder 576)
  - Clippings about Adams (in Series II), 1949-1962 (Box 12, Folder 586-587)
  - Selected Essays, galleys, corrected (in Series II), 1966-1967 (Folder 595 (Broadside))
  - Selected Essays, reviews, clippings and printed material (in Series II), 1967-1968 (Box 11, Folder 577-579)
  - Selected Essays, reviews and clippings on National Book Award (in Series II), 1967-1968 (Box 12, Folder 588)
  - Review on James Joyce's Ulysses: A Study by Stuart Gilbert (from New York Times Book Review ) (in Series II), 1931 January 18 (Box 11, Folder 580)
  - Clippings on T.S. Eliot (in Series V), 1948-1949 (Box 11, Folder 581)
  - Clippings on Ezra Pound and Bollingen Prize (in Series V), 1949 (Box 11, Folder 582-583)
  - Clippings on Wallace Stevens, William Carlos Williams and various clippings on poetry (in Series V), 1949, 1954, undated (Box 11, Folder 584)
  - Clippings on poetry (in Series V), undated (Box 12, Folder 589)
  - Miscellaneous clippings (in Series V), undated (Box 11, Folder 585)
  - Miscellaneous clippings (in Series V), 1899-1964 undated (Box 12, Folder 590-593)
- Restricted Fragile, 0.21 linear feet (1 box)
  Conditions Governing Access
  Restricted fragile material. Reference surrogates have been substituted in the main files. Consult Access Services for further information.
  - Box 1, Folder 27 (Box 13, Folder 596)
  - Box 1, Folder 90 (Box 13, Folder 597)
  - Box 2, Folder 114 (Box 13, Folder 598)
  - Box 2, Folder 131 (Box 13, Folder 599)
  - Box 3, Folder 230 (Box 13, Folder 600)
  - Box 3, Folder 241 (Box 13, Folder 601)
  - Box 5, Folders 413-415 (Box 13, Folder 602)
  - Box 5, Folder 442 (Box 13, Folder 603)
  - Box 5, Folder 444 (Box 13, Folder 604)
  - Box 5, Folders 449-453 (Box 13, Folder 605-607)
  - Box 6, Folder 497 (Box 13, Folder 608)
  - Box 6, Folder 498 (Box 13, Folder 609)
  - Box 7, Folder 512 (Box 13, Folder 610)